<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Bug Alert - Confluence</title><link href="https://bugalert.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://bugalert.org/feeds/confluence.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://bugalert.org/</id><updated>2022-07-20T10:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle>A nonprofit service for alerting security and IT professionals of high-impact and 0day vulnerabilities.</subtitle><entry><title>Multiple Vulnerabilities in Atlassian Products (CVE-2022-26136, CVE-2022-26137, CVE-2022-26138)</title><link href="https://bugalert.org/content/notices/2022-07-20-atlassian.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-20T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-20T10:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bug Alert Contributors</name></author><id>tag:bugalert.org,2022-07-20:/content/notices/2022-07-20-atlassian.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Multiple Vulnerabilities have been disclosed in Atlassian Products. A hardcoded credential vulnerability in Questions for Confluence, and Servlet Filter Bypass Vulnerabilities have been found in multiple Atlassian products that may enable Authentication Bypasses, XSS Attacks, and CORS attacks. These vulnerabilites have been assigned a bug alert severity of 'very high'. Atlassian recommends patching affected installations immediately.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, July 20th, 2022, &lt;a href="https://confluence.atlassian.com/security/july-2022-atlassian-security-advisories-overview-1142446703.html"&gt;Atlassian released a Security Advisory&lt;/a&gt; stating that a hardcoded credential vulnerability exists in the Questions for Confluence application, as well as Servlet Filter bypasses in both first and third party applications tied to multiple Atlassian products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardcoded credential vulnerability stems from the use of the Questions for Confluence application with the &lt;code&gt;disabledsystemuser&lt;/code&gt; account. The fix here is to update the Questions for Confluence app to a non-vulnerable version, or to disable/delete this account. &lt;strong&gt;Uninstalling the Questions for Confluence application does not remediate this vulnerability.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To check for use of the &lt;code&gt;disabledsystemuser&lt;/code&gt; account, follow instructions found &lt;a href="https://confluence.atlassian.com/confkb/how-to-get-a-list-of-users-with-their-last-logon-times-985499701.html"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time they have not released any specifics as to what the exact vulnerable endpoint is for the servlet bypasses, or any indicators of compromise that could lead defenders to believe they have been exploited. The current fix is to patch to the level indicated in the advisory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If exploited, these servlet bypass vulnerabilities may enable attackers to perform an Authentication Bypass, Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) Attacks, or Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS) bypass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have feedback (did you agree/disagree that a notice should have been sent?) or questions, please comment on the discussion thread linked below. This notice cost the project approximately $100 USD to send. If you would like to support the project, &lt;a href="https://bugalert.org/content/pages/financial-support.html"&gt;you can learn more here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Services &amp; System Applications"></category><category term="Confluence"></category><category term="Jira"></category><category term="Bitbucket"></category><category term="Bamboo"></category><category term="Fisheye"></category><category term="Crowd"></category><category term="Atlassian"></category><category term="Very High Severity"></category></entry><entry><title>Unauthenticated Remote Code Execution in Atlassian Confluence (CVE-2022-26134)</title><link href="https://bugalert.org/content/notices/2022-06-02-confluence.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-02T17:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-02T17:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bug Alert Contributors</name></author><id>tag:bugalert.org,2022-06-02:/content/notices/2022-06-02-confluence.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An unauthenticated remote code execution flaw has been found, and is being actively exploited, in Atlassian Confluence, and has been assigned a bug alert severity of 'very high'. Atlassian recommends removing installations from the Internet immediately.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, June 2nd, 2022, &lt;a href="https://confluence.atlassian.com/doc/confluence-security-advisory-2022-06-02-1130377146.html"&gt;Atlassian released a Security Advisory&lt;/a&gt; stating that Confluence Server and Data Center editions are vulnerable to an Unauthenticated Remote Code Execution vulnerability &lt;strong&gt;that is under active exploitation&lt;/strong&gt;. At this time they have not released any specifics as to what the exact vulnerable endpoint is, or any indicators of compromise that could lead defenders to believe they have been exploited. There is currently no fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a patch has been made available, it's likely that additional attackers will inspect the differences in the application binaries between the fixed and vulnerable versions, and develop attack methods rapidly. This post will be updated as information becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, Atlassian is advising customers to remove Confluence Server and Data Center from being available from the Internet, either by shutting them down, or by firewalling them off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This vulnerability been assigned CVE-2022-26134. &lt;del&gt;Patches are not yet available from the vendor&lt;/del&gt; (see last update for patch links). This notice will be updated when they are published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Update as of June 2nd, 10:00PM New York time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity firm Volexity has &lt;a href="https://www.volexity.com/blog/2022/06/02/zero-day-exploitation-of-atlassian-confluence/"&gt;published a blog post&lt;/a&gt; detailing how they originally found this vulnerability being used in the wild, prior to reporting it to Atlassian. Their write-up includes IP ranges the attackers utilized, as well as some additional background information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States Cybersecurity &amp;amp; Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has added this flaw to its list of &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/known-exploited-vulnerabilities-catalog"&gt;known exploited vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt; with a deadline for remediation of Friday, June 3rd, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;As of this update, there is still no patch available.&lt;/del&gt; Confluence administrators are urged to remove public-facing installations from the Internet as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Update as of June 3rd, 2:30PM New York time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.atlassian.com/software/confluence/download-archives"&gt;Patches are now available from Atlassian.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have feedback (did you agree/disagree that a notice should have been sent?) or questions, please comment on the discussion thread linked below. This notice cost the project approximately $100 USD to send. If you would like to support the project, &lt;a href="https://bugalert.org/content/pages/financial-support.html"&gt;you can learn more here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Services &amp; System Applications"></category><category term="Confluence"></category><category term="Atlassian"></category><category term="Very High Severity"></category></entry></feed>