<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Bug Alert - polkit</title><link href="https://bugalert.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://bugalert.org/feeds/polkit.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://bugalert.org/</id><updated>2022-01-25T20:42:00+00:00</updated><subtitle>A nonprofit service for alerting security and IT professionals of high-impact and 0day vulnerabilities.</subtitle><entry><title>Local privilege escalation in pkexec, a core Linux system component</title><link href="https://bugalert.org/content/notices/2022-01-25-pkexec.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-01-25T20:42:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-25T20:42:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bug Alert Contributors</name></author><id>tag:bugalert.org,2022-01-25:/content/notices/2022-01-25-pkexec.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A local privilege escalation bug (from any user to root) has been found polkit's pkexec, and exploit code is available. This binary is a SUID root program available on every major Linux distro, and is most commonly installed if a GUI is present. The flaw has been assigned a bug alert severity of 'very high'.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, January 25th, 2022, &lt;a href="https://blog.qualys.com/vulnerabilities-threat-research/2022/01/25/pwnkit-local-privilege-escalation-vulnerability-discovered-in-polkits-pkexec-cve-2021-4034"&gt;Qualys published a blog post detailing an issue they identified&lt;/a&gt; within pkexec, a core component of polkit (formerly known as PolicyKit). In the time since Qualys disclosed this issue, &lt;a href="https://haxx.in/files/blasty-vs-pkexec.c"&gt;exploit code&lt;/a&gt; has been made available. The pkexec binary is &lt;em&gt;most commonly&lt;/em&gt; installed with Linux GUI components and may not be present on servers that run 'minimal' OS installs. This post will be updated as more information becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PwnKit, as this vulnerability is being called, has been assigned CVE-2021-4034. Patches are available now for most Linux distributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to &lt;a href="https://github.com/mattcobb"&gt;Matt Cobb&lt;/a&gt; for reporting this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was Bug Alert's first notice. If you have feedback (did you agree/disagree that a notice should have been sent?) or questions, please comment on the discussion thread linked below. This notice cost the project approximately $120 USD to send. If you would like to support the project, &lt;a href="https://bugalert.org/content/pages/financial-support.html"&gt;you can learn more here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Operating Systems"></category><category term="pkexec"></category><category term="polkit"></category><category term="Pwnkit"></category><category term="Linux"></category><category term="Very High Severity"></category></entry></feed>