<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Bug Alert - SAP</title><link href="https://bugalert.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://bugalert.org/feeds/sap.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://bugalert.org/</id><updated>2022-02-08T10:02:00+00:00</updated><subtitle>A nonprofit service for alerting security and IT professionals of high-impact and 0day vulnerabilities.</subtitle><entry><title>Unauthenticated user impersonation (auth bypass) in SAP</title><link href="https://bugalert.org/content/notices/2022-02-08-sap.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-02-08T10:02:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-08T10:02:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bug Alert Contributors</name></author><id>tag:bugalert.org,2022-02-08:/content/notices/2022-02-08-sap.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A request smuggling issue in SAP NetWeaver, SAP Content Server, and SAP Web Dispatcher allows unauthenticated user impersonation. These systems are commonly Internet-facing. The flaw has been assigned a bug alert severity of 'critical', and the vendor has supplied patches.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, February 8, 2022, &lt;a href="https://blogs.sap.com/2022/02/08/sap-partners-with-onapsis-to-identify-and-patch-cybersecurity-vulnerabilities/"&gt;SAP published a notice detailing a major request smuggling flaw&lt;/a&gt; within their SAP NetWeaver, SAP Content Server, and SAP Web Dispatcher products, which SAP claims could lead to authentication bypass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publicly available documentation is scarce, but the Bug Alert team has analyzed &lt;a href="https://github.com/Onapsis/onapsis_icmad_scanner/blob/master/src/ICMAD_scanner.py"&gt;the PoC&lt;/a&gt; and SAP documentation. It appears that SAP &lt;a href="https://help.sap.com/viewer/e815bb97839a4d83be6c4fca48ee5777/7.5.21/en-US/4a47abb3e1f41cd4e10000000a421937.html"&gt;can utilize the &lt;code&gt;REMOTE_USER&lt;/code&gt; header&lt;/a&gt; (which is usually stripped from untrusted traffic) to authenticate a user through an authenticating proxy or SSO module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, publicly available information is limited at this time, but it appears likely that this request smuggling issue could be utilized to insert the &lt;code&gt;REMOTE_USER&lt;/code&gt; request header and impersonate another SAP user, including the present-by-default 'Administrator' account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This vulnerability been assigned CVE-2022-22536. Patches are available now from the vendor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have feedback (did you agree/disagree that a notice should have been sent?) or questions, please comment on the discussion thread linked below. This notice cost the project approximately $150 USD to send. If you would like to support the project, &lt;a href="https://bugalert.org/content/pages/financial-support.html"&gt;you can learn more here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Services &amp; System Applications"></category><category term="SAP"></category><category term="CVE-2022-22536"></category><category term="Critical Severity"></category></entry></feed>